Muste, A. J. Papers on Microfilm 5975 mf
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
A. J. Muste Papers on Microfilm
1905-1967
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Muste, A. J.
5975 mf
4.33 cubic feet
39 microfilm reels
Papers, microfilm.
The papers of A.J. Muste consist of correspondence, autobiographical materials, book reviews, speeches, articles, pamphlets, and clippings. The correspondence (1958-1967), divided into private correspondence and business papers, forms the bulk of the collection. Numerous individuals and organizations are represented in the correspondence, which includes information about George Keenan, Linus Pauling, Anatol Rapaport, A. Philip Randolph, Morton Sobell, the Congress of Racial Equality (CORE), the World Peace Brigade, Pendle Hill, the Hudson Institute, and the Fellowship of Reconciliation. The records of Liberation Magazine and information about the San Francisco to Moscow Walk, the Omaha Action, the Polaris Action, and tax resistance are also in the collection.
5743744
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, September 26, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, March 29, 2016
Biographical / Historical
A.J. Muste (1885-1967), born Abraham Johannes Muste in the province of Zeeland, the Netherlands, came to the United States in 1891 when the Muste family settled in Grand Rapids, Michigan. In 1909, Muste was ordained a minister in the Dutch Reformed Church, but eight years later he became a member of the Society of Friends. During World War I, Muste's refusal to abandon his pacifist position led to his forced resignation from the Central Congregational Church in Newtonville, Massachusetts.
Muste's involvement as a labor organizer began in 1919 when he led strikes in the textile mills of Lawrence, Massachusetts. He became the director of the Brookwood Labor College in Katonah, New York, remaining there until 1931. Muste served as national chairman of the Fellowship of Reconciliation (FOR), 1926-1929. He was one of the founders of the Conference for Progressive Labor Action (CPLA) in 1929 and in 1934 facilitated the merger of the CPLA with the Trotskyists to form the short-lived Workers Party of America. Muste was director of the Presbyterian Labor Temple from 1937 to 1940. In 1940 he became executive director of the FOR, a position he held until his retirement in 1953, when he was made director emeritus. From 1948 to 1953 he served as secretary of the Ohio Peacemakers, a radical pacifist group. He was also a member of the executive committee of the War Resisters League, one of the international chairmen of the World Peace Brigade, and helped organize the Committee for Nonviolent Action (CNVA), on which he later served as chairman. For several years he was an editor of Liberation magazine.
Throughout his "retirement," Muste devoted his considerable energies to the civil rights and peace movements. In the early 1960s he had given much of his attention to the development of a radical, politically relevant, nonviolent movement. During the escalation of the Vietnam War in 1964 and 1965, Muste played a major role in organizing rallies, vigils, and marches to protest the expanding involvement of US military forces in Vietnam. In 1966, Muste went to Saigon with five other pacifists; one year later he traveled to Hanoi to meet with North Vietnamese leaders to find ways to end the war. At the time of his death in February 1967, he was the founding chairmen of the Spring Mobilization Committee to End the War in Vietnam.
Scope and Contents
The correspondence (1958-1967), divided into private correspondence and business papers, forms the bulk of the collection. Numerous individuals and organizations are represented in the correspondence, which includes information about George Keenan, Linus Pauling, Anatol Rapaport, A. Philip Randolph, Morton Sobell, the Congress of Racial Equality (CORE), the World Peace Brigade, Pendle Hill, the Hudson Institute, and the Fellowship of Reconciliation.
The records of Liberation Magazine and information about the San Francisco to Moscow Walk, the Omaha Action, the Polaris Action, and tax resistance are also in the collection.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Muste, A. J. (Abraham John), 1885-1967.
5743744
- Autobiographical material, 1920 to date (Reel 1)
  - Autobiographical material, 1 (Reel 1)
  - Material about A.J. Muste, 1920-1966; 2 (Reel 1)
  - "Liberty and Justice for All"--a study by Elizabeth Tucker, 1957; 3 (Reel 1)
  - Material about him, 1967 (Reel 1)
    - Tributes, 1967; 4 (Reel 1)
    - Family Correspondence, 1967; 5 (Reel 1)
    - Memorial Fund, 1967; 6 (Reel 1)
    - Testimonial, 1967; 7 (Reel 1)
      Scope and Contents
      March 12, 1967.
    - Material about him, 1967; 8 (Reel 1)
      1967 to date
- Correspondence, personal, 1940-1967; 9 (Reel 1)
- Tax refusal (Reel 2)
  - A.J. Muste case (Harrop Freeman, attorney), 1956-1962; 1 (Reel 2)
  - Correspondence, releases, reprints, etc., 1949-1965; 2 (Reel 2)
    1966-67 and no date
  - Correspondence, releases, etc., 1966-1967; 3 (Reel 2)
- Legal charge (United States v. Muste, Omaha action), 1959; 4 (Reel 2)
- Clippings marked by A.J. Muste (misc.), 5 (Reel 2)
- Material on Brookwood Labor College: (Reel 2)
  - Minutes, releases, courses, 1921-1937; 6 (Reel 2)
  - Brookwood controversy, 1928; 7 (Reel 2)
  - Documents Dealing with the Brookwood Faculty Controversy, by Cara Cook@, 1933; 8 (Reel 2)
  - Brookwood experience of C. Cook. Tribute to A.J. Muste@, 9 (Reel 2)
  - Material about Brookwood, 10 (Reel 2)
- Speeches, 1905-1960: (Reel 3)
  - Valedictory address, 1905; 1 (Reel 3)
  - Speeches, 1937-1939; 2 (Reel 3)
  - Labor Temple, 1939; 3 (Reel 3)
  - Speeches, 1940-1941; 4 (Reel 3)
  - Pendle Hill Lectures, 1941; 5 (Reel 3)
  - Speeches, 1942; 6 (Reel 3)
  - New Brunswick Seminary Lectures, 1944; 7 (Reel 3)
  - Pendle Hill Lectures on the Peace Testimony, 1954; 8 (Reel 3)
- Speeches, 1961-1967; 9 (Reel 3)
  and no date
- Speeches and writings, 1948-1967 (Reel 3)
  - Quotations and speech material, 10 (Reel 3)
  - Releases written for Peacemakers, 1948-1952; 11 (Reel 3)
  - Releases, written for Church Peace Mission, 1950-1953; 1 (Reel 4)
  - Releases, 1954-1967; 2 (Reel 4)
  - Book Reviews (written by A.J. Muste), 3 (Reel 4)
  - Articles, 1922-1930; 4 (Reel 4)
  - Articles, 1931-1947; 5 (Reel 4)
  - Articles, 1948-1956; 6 (Reel 4)
  - Articles, 1948-1956; 1 (Reel 5)
  - Articles, 1957-1964; 2 (Reel 5)
  - Articles, 1965-1967; 3 (Reel 5)
  - Articles, 4 (Reel 5)
    no date
  - Articles, 1 (Reel 6)
    no date continued
- Tape recordings (not filmed), 2 (Reel 6)
- Pamphlets, 1930-1967; 3 (Reel 6)
- Correspondence before 1937, 4 (Reel 6)
- Correspondence, 1937-1940; 5 (Reel 6)
- Correspondence (1958-1963) (Reel 6)
  - A (General), 6 (Reel 6)
  - Acts for Peace, 7 (Reel 6)
  - Adams, Robert T., 8 (Reel 6)
  - Addresses (postal), 1 (Reel 7)
  - Advance, 2 (Reel 7)
  - Africa, economic development, 3 (Reel 7)
  - Africa Freedom Action Project (see World Peace Brigade), 4 (Reel 7)
  - Africa (Podea meeting, 1959), 5 (Reel 7)
  - African conference on nonviolence, 6 (Reel 7)
  - African nonviolent movement, 7 (Reel 7)
  - American Committee on Africa, 8 (Reel 7)
  - American Forum, 9 (Reel 7)
  - American Friends Service Committee, 10 (Reel 7)
  - American Friends ervice Committee (Avon Institute), 11 (Reel 7)
  - American Friends Service Committee (see also Meachan, Stewart), 12 (Reel 7)
  - American Friends Service Committee (California), 13 (Reel 7)
  - American Labor Education Service, 14 (Reel 7)
  - American Legion, 15 (Reel 7)
  - Amsterdam Conference, 16 (Reel 7)
  - Andrews, David, 17 (Reel 7)
  - B (General), 18 (Reel 7)
  - Bear Mountain statement, 19 (Reel 7)
  - Bigelow, Albert, 20 (Reel 7)
  - Bollens, John (see John Birch Society), 21 (Reel 7)
  - Bomb test suits, 22 (Reel 7)
  - Briefing on CBR (chemical, biological and radiological warfare), 23 (Reel 7)
  - Bristah, James, 24 (Reel 7)
  - Brodman, Joseph, 25 (Reel 7)
  - Brooke, Anthony, 26 (Reel 7)
  - Buckeburg, Germany (Conference), 27 (Reel 7)
  - Butterfield, Herbert, 28 (Reel 7)
  - C (General), 29 (Reel 7)
  - Cables, 30 (Reel 7)
  - Campaign against Atomic Weapons (Danish), 31 (Reel 7)
  - Campaign for Nuclear Disarmament, 32 (Reel 7)
  - Canadian Peace Research Institute (Pugwash), 33 (Reel 7)
  - Capital punishment, 34 (Reel 7)
  - Carolan, William, 35 (Reel 7)
  - Catholic Worker, 36 (Reel 7)
  - Central Committee for Conscientious Objectors, 37 (Reel 7)
  - Challenge, 38 (Reel 7)
  - Chandy, K.K., 39 (Reel 7)
  - CBR (chemical, biological and radiological warfare) see Briefing on CBR, 40 (Reel 7)
  - Chen, John, 41 (Reel 7)
  - Cheyenne (missile site), 42 (Reel 7)
  - Chicago Conference on Nonviolence in the 1960s, 43 (Reel 7)
  - Christian Approach to Nuclear War version, financial, orders, promotion, releases, signer and sponsors, 1 (Reel 8)
  - Christian Century, 2 (Reel 8)
  - Christian Peace Conference, 3 (Reel 8)
  - Church Peace Mission:, 4 (Reel 8)
    - Annual Meetings, 5 (Reel 8)
    - Annual report of the Missioner (A.J. Muste), 6 (Reel 8)
    - Baptist Peace Fellowship, 7 (Reel 8)
    - Brochure: Bulletin, 8 (Reel 8)
    - Conference file, 9 (Reel 8)
    - Constituent representation, 10 (Reel 8)
    - Detroit study papers, 1950; 11 (Reel 8)
      Area I, II, Miller papers, Muste comment, miscellaneous, Schlip (paper not used)
    - East-West Churchmen's meeting (proposed), 12 (Reel 8)
    - Evanston conference (financial), 1 (Reel 9)
    - Executive Committee, minutes, etc., 2 (Reel 9)
    - Financial, 3 (Reel 9)
    - Friends Peace Committee, 4 (Reel 9)
    - General correspondence, 5 (Reel 9)
    - General literature orders, etc., 1 (Reel 10)
    - History, evaluation, etc. of Church Peace Mission, 2 (Reel 10)
    - Literature and publications (correspondence), 3 (Reel 10)
    - Message orders, 4 (Reel 10)
    - Miscellaneous report (before 1958, and 1958-1963), 5 (Reel 10)
    - Mueller, Heinz-Albrecht, 6 (Reel 10)
    - 1962 National Conference (April 10 Meeting), 7 (Reel 10)
    - New York, 8 (Reel 10)
    - Organization and officers, 9 (Reel 10)
    - Peachey, Paul, 10 (Reel 10)
    - Questionnaires, 11 (Reel 10)
    - Releases, 12 (Reel 10)
    - Report on study conference planning, 1961; 13 (Reel 10)
    - Secretary, 14 (Reel 10)
    - Sponsor replies, 15 (Reel 10)
    - Treasurer, 16 (Reel 10)
    - United Presbyterian Peace Fellowship, 17 (Reel 10)
    - Audio Visual-three tape recordings (DeKretser, Dahlberg, Davidon, 18 (Reel 10)
  - Citizens Committee for Equal Rights for Voluntary Hospital Employees, 19 (Reel 10)
  - Citizens Committee for a $1.50 Minimum Hourly Wage in New York City, 20 (Reel 10)
  - Civil Defense, 21 (Reel 10)
  - Civil Defense Protest Committee (financial, sponsors, signer), 22 (Reel 10)
  - Civil Liberties Conference (proposed), 23 (Reel 10)
  - Cleveland study conference, 24 (Reel 10)
  - Clippings of interest to A.J. Muste, 25 (Reel 10)
  - College Cevenol, 26 (Reel 10)
  - College Peace Union, 27 (Reel 10)
  - Collins, Canon John, 28 (Reel 10)
  - Colloquy (October 1959)-possible, theological, 1960, 1959-1960; 29 (Reel 10)
  - Commentary, 30 (Reel 10)
  - Committee for Nonviolent Action (CNVA), 31 (Reel 10)
  - CNVA-Cheyenne Project, 32 (Reel 10)
  - CNVA-Christmas Island Project, 1 (Reel 11)
  - CNVA-Correspondence to Muste, 2 (Reel 11)
  - CNVA-Directions, 3 (Reel 11)
  - CNVA-Executive committee, 4 (Reel 11)
  - CNVA-Financial, 5 (Reel 11)
  - Committee for Nonviolent Action (continued), 6 (Reel 11)
  - CNVA-General, 7 (Reel 11)
  - CNVA-London to Leningrad Project (Financial, Working, etc.), 8 (Reel 11)
  - CNVA-Miscellaneous reports, etc., 9 (Reel 11)
  - CNVA-Nashville to Washington Walk, Spring 1962, 10 (Reel 11)
  - CNVA-Nonviolent action against nuclear weapons (miscellaneous), 11 (Reel 11)
  - CNVA-Omaha action (see Omaha project), 12 (Reel 11)
  - CNVA-Polaris Action (see Polaris project and Lyttle, Bradford J.), 13 (Reel 11)
  - CNVA-Quebec-Washington-Guantanamo Walk, 14 (Reel 11)
  - CNVA- Q-W-G Walk, Albany, Georgia, 15 (Reel 11)
  - CNVA- Q-W-G Walk, Albany log (incomplete), 1 (Reel 12)
  - CNVA- Q-W-G Walk, clippings, 2 (Reel 12)
  - CNVA- Q-W-G Walk-Correspondence with sheriffs and other government officials, 3 (Reel 12)
  - CNVA- Q-W-G Walk-Financial, 4 (Reel 12)
  - CNVA- Q-W-G Walk-General correspondence, 5 (Reel 12)
  - CNVA- Q-W-G Walk-Memos sent to National Committee members and walkers, 6 (Reel 12)
  - CNVA- Q-W-G Walk-Pamphlets, releases, and schedules, 7 (Reel 12)
  - CNVA- Q-W-G Walk-Walk Reports, 8 (Reel 12)
  - CNVA-San Francisco to Moscow Walk for Peace-Financial, Follow-Up, 9 (Reel 12)
  - CNVA-San Francisco to Moscow Walk for Peace-Personnel, photographs, 10 (Reel 12)
  - CNVA-Swann, Robert, 11 (Reel 12)
  - CNVA-Taxes, 12 (Reel 12)
  - CNVA-Visit of the Soviet Peace Committee to the USA (February 1964), 13 (Reel 12)
  - CNVA-Weekly Bulletin, 14 (Reel 12)
  - CNVA, New England, 15 (Reel 12)
  - CNVA, West, 16 (Reel 12)
  - Committee for Return of Confiscated German and Japanese Property, 17 (Reel 12)
  - Conscientious objection, 1 (Reel 13)
  - Consultative Peace Council, 2 (Reel 13)
  - Correspondent, 3 (Reel 13)
  - Council for a Livable World, 4 (Reel 13)
  - Cuba, 5 (Reel 13)
    - Cuban defense committee, 6 (Reel 13)
    - Cuban government pamphlets, 7 (Reel 13)
    - Fair Play for Cuba Committee (see Fair Play for Cuba Committee), 8 (Reel 13)
    - Medicine for Cuba, 9 (Reel 13)
    - Nonviolent Committee for Cuban Independence, 10 (Reel 13)
  - D (General), 11 (Reel 13)
  - Detrick (Fort Detrick) Direct Action Committee against Nuclear War, 12 (Reel 13)
  - Direct action projects, 13 (Reel 13)
  - Disarmament, 14 (Reel 13)
  - Disarmament News, 15 (Reel 13)
  - Dissent, 16 (Reel 13)
  - Dolci, Danilo, 17 (Reel 13)
  - Dos Passos, John, 18 (Reel 13)
  - Douglas, Deborah, 19 (Reel 13)
  - Dugger, Ronnie, 20 (Reel 13)
  - E (General), 21 (Reel 13)
  - East Harlem Protestant Parish, 22 (Reel 13)
  - East Harlem Protestant Parish-Narcotics Committee (see Harlem Narcotics Conference), 23 (Reel 13)
  - East-West Christian Leaders' Conference, 24 (Reel 13)
  - Easter Peace Projects, 25 (Reel 13)
  - Eddy, Norman (see Harlem Narcotics Committee), 26 (Reel 13)
  - Engagements, 1961; 1 (Reel 14)
    possible and refused
  - France (Anti-nuclear war demonstrations), 18 (Reel 15)
  - Ethical Culture, Society for, 2 (Reel 14)
  - Evangelical United Brethren, 3 (Reel 14)
  - Frankfort, 19 (Reel 15)
  - F (General), 4 (Reel 14)
  - Frankfort Conference news, 1 (Reel 16)
  - Facci, Joseph (article), 5 (Reel 14)
  - Freedom House, 2 (Reel 16)
  - Fair Play for Cuba Committee, 6 (Reel 14)
  - Friends Committee on National Legislation (FCNL), 3 (Reel 16)
  - Fellowship of Reconciliation, 7 (Reel 14)
  - Friends Journal, 4 (Reel 16)
  - Friends Peace Committee (British) Fromm, Erich, 5 (Reel 16)
  - National, 8 (Reel 14)
  - Fulcrum Press, 6 (Reel 16)
  - F.O.R., 9 (Reel 14)
  - Fund appeals, 7 (Reel 16)
  - Church secretary position, 10 (Reel 14)
  - G (General), 8 (Reel 16)
  - Committees: On organization, 11 (Reel 14)
  - Gandhi Marg, 9 (Reel 16)
  - National Council, Executive Committee (minutes, etc.), 12 (Reel 14)
  - Gandhi Memorial in New York City, 10 (Reel 16)
  - Financial and personal, 13 (Reel 14)
  - Gandhi Peace Foundation (India conference on anti-nuclear arms), 11 (Reel 16)
  - North American Committee, minutes, 14 (Reel 14)
  - Conferences, 1958-1963; 15 (Reel 14)
    Fall 1958, Fall 1961, Fall 1962, Summer 1963
  - General Strike for peace, 12 (Reel 16)
  - Frost, Henry, 16 (Reel 14)
  - Geneva (trip of American pacifists), 13 (Reel 16)
  - German Friends, 14 (Reel 16)
  - General, 17 (Reel 14)
  - Japan, 18 (Reel 14)
  - Golden Rule (ship), 15 (Reel 16)
  - Gravem, Axel B., 16 (Reel 16)
  - National Staff, 19 (Reel 14)
  - Greater New York peace groups (conference of), 17 (Reel 16)
  - National (cont.), 20 (Reel 14)
  - Greene, Felix, 18 (Reel 16)
  - New members (or prospects), 21 (Reel 14)
  - H (General), 19 (Reel 16)
  - November 11, 1960, meeting, 22 (Reel 14)
  - Picnic, 1960; 23 (Reel 14)
  - Hall, Francis (see Powell House), 20 (Reel 16)
  - Hammond, William, request, 21 (Reel 16)
  - Publications (Aids for Peace Action, Fieldworker), 24 (Reel 14)
  - Harlem Narcotics Committee, 22 (Reel 16)
  - Regional conference, 1960; 25 (Reel 14)
  - Regional offices (Midwest), 26 (Reel 14)
  - Hefner, William (Peace Party), 23 (Reel 16)
  - Shelters for the Shelterless, 27 (Reel 14)
  - Highlander Folk School, 24 (Reel 16)
  - Soper, Donald, dinner, 28 (Reel 14)
  - Hiroshima Dancers, 25 (Reel 16)
  - Turn Toward Peace (New York), 29 (Reel 14)
  - Hiroshima Day, 26 (Reel 16)
  - New York, 30 (Reel 14)
  - Hiroshima Peace Declaration, 27 (Reel 16)
  - Hiroshima-Auschwitz Peace March, 1963, 28 (Reel 16)
  - F.O.R. New York (1, 2), 1 (Reel 15)
  - Hoffman, Hallock, 29 (Reel 16)
  - Agenda, 2 (Reel 15)
  - Annual dinner, 1959, 1961, 1962, 1959-1962; 3 (Reel 15)
  - Hoover, J. Edgar, 30 (Reel 16)
  - New York (cont.), 4 (Reel 15)
  - Hospital Workers, 31 (Reel 16)
  - Annual dinner, 1963; 5 (Reel 15)
  - House Un-American Activities Committee, opposition to, 32 (Reel 16)
  - Appeal, response to Thanksgiving appeal, 6 (Reel 15)
  - Howard, Asbury (case and statement), 33 (Reel 16)
  - Committees: Council, 7 (Reel 15)
  - Hudson Institute, 34 (Reel 16)
  - India, 35 (Reel 16)
  - Executive committee, 8 (Reel 15)
  - Interchurch Center, 36 (Reel 16)
  - Conferences, Fall 1962, 9 (Reel 15)
  - International Liaison Committee of Peace (ILCOP), 37 (Reel 16)
  - Financial, 10 (Reel 15)
  - J (General), 38 (Reel 16)
  - Kenworthy, Leonard, 11 (Reel 15)
  - Jack, Homer A., 39 (Reel 16)
  - Retreat, 1961; 12 (Reel 15)
  - Jacobson, Julius, 40 (Reel 16)
  - International, 13 (Reel 15)
  - I.F.O.R. (1,2), 14 (Reel 15)
  - Japan Council Against Atomic and Hydrogen Bombs, 41 (Reel 16)
  - Eastman, Philip, 15 (Reel 15)
  - John Birch Society, 42 (Reel 16)
  - Field, George (see Freedom House), 16 (Reel 15)
  - K (General), 43 (Reel 16)
  - Kaunda, Kenneth, 44 (Reel 16)
  - Fort Detrick (see Detrick), 17 (Reel 15)
  - Kennedy, John F., 45 (Reel 16)
  - King, Martin Luther, 46 (Reel 16)
  - King-Hall, Stephen, 47 (Reel 16)
  - Kinzua Dam, 48 (Reel 16)
  - Kloppenburg, Heinz, 49 (Reel 16)
  - Kohn, Lucile, 50 (Reel 16)
    see American Labor Education Service
  - Koinonia Farm, 51 (Reel 16)
  - Kora, Tomi, 52 (Reel 16)
  - Kruse, John, 53 (Reel 16)
  - L (General), 54 (Reel 16)
  - Lawson, James, 1 (Reel 17)
  - Lecoin, Louis, 2 (Reel 17)
  - Lens, Sidney, 3 (Reel 17)
  - Lerner, Max, 4 (Reel 17)
  - Lester, Muriel, 5 (Reel 17)
  - Letters to editors, 6 (Reel 17)
  - Liberation, 7 (Reel 17)
    - Editorial board meetings, 1960; 8 (Reel 17)
    - Editorial board minutes, 1959-1963; 9 (Reel 17)
    - Publication exchanges, 10 (Reel 17)
    - Financial correspondence regarding appeals, etc., 1962-1963; 11 (Reel 17)
    - Integration, correspondence, 12 (Reel 17)
    - Office personnel, correspondence, 13 (Reel 17)
    - Promotion, promotional materials, 14 (Reel 17)
    - Prospectus for September 1959 issue, 15 (Reel 17)
    - Reprints, correspondence, 1959-1960; 16 (Reel 17)
    - Correspondence regarding New York Times issue, 1959; 17 (Reel 17)
      March 19, 1959.
    - Correspondence, general, 1960-1966; 18 (Reel 17)
    - Correspondence relating to articles, 1958-1966; 1 (Reel 18)
    - Editorials, by editors, dated by appearance in Liberation, 2 (Reel 18)
    - Editorials and articles by A.J. Muste, 3 (Reel 18)
    - Reprints, flyers, etc., 4 (Reel 18)
    - Miscellaneous, 5 (Reel 18)
  - London Conference, 1961 (disarmament and world tensions), 6 (Reel 18)
  - Lutheran Peace Fellowship, 7 (Reel 18)
  - Lyttle, Bradford J., 8 (Reel 18)
  - M (General), 9 (Reel 18)
  - McCrackin, Maurice (case and replies), 10 (Reel 18)
  - McGovern, (Senator) George, 11 (Reel 18)
  - March on Washington, 12 (Reel 18)
  - May Day Celebration, 13 (Reel 18)
  - May Day Committee, 14 (Reel 18)
    see Union Square May Day Committee
  - Mayer, Peter (Orion Press), 15 (Reel 18)
  - Meachan, Stewart, 16 (Reel 18)
    see also American Friends Service Committee
  - The Meeting School, 17 (Reel 18)
  - Meigs, Mary, 18 (Reel 18)
  - Metropolitan Board for Conscientious Objectors, 19 (Reel 18)
  - Minority of One, 20 (Reel 18)
  - Missile Bases, 21 (Reel 18)
  - Modern Community Developers, Inc., 22 (Reel 18)
  - Monroe Defendants, Committee to Aid, 23 (Reel 18)
  - Moral rearmament, 24 (Reel 18)
  - N (General), 25 (Reel 18)
  - National Committee to Abolish the Un-American Activities Committee, 26 (Reel 18)
    see also House Un-American Activities Committee, opposition to
  - National Council for Peace and against Nuclear Weapons, 27 (Reel 18)
  - National Council for Prevention of War, 28 (Reel 18)
  - National Council for American-Soviet Friendship, 29 (Reel 18)
  - National Council of Churches, 30 (Reel 18)
  - Nehru, Madame, 31 (Reel 18)
  - New International Year-book, 32 (Reel 18)
  - New University thought, 33 (Reel 18)
  - New York Friends group, 34 (Reel 18)
  - New York Peace Information Center, 35 (Reel 18)
  - Nuclear testing moratorium, 36 (Reel 18)
  - O (General), 37 (Reel 18)
  - Omaha project, 38 (Reel 18)
    - General (1), 39 (Reel 18)
    - General (2), 1 (Reel 19)
    - Financial, 2 (Reel 19)
    - Follow-up, 3 (Reel 19)
    - Trial, 4 (Reel 19)
  - One Hundred Days for Peace, 5 (Reel 19)
  - Our Generation against Nuclear War, 6 (Reel 19)
  - Oxford Conference, 7 (Reel 19)
  - P (General), 8 (Reel 19)
  - Pacifica Research Center, 9 (Reel 19)
  - Pacifism, inquiries about, 10 (Reel 19)
  - Pacifist blueprints for peace, 11 (Reel 19)
  - Pacifist publications, 12 (Reel 19)
  - Pacifist songbook, 13 (Reel 19)
  - Pacifist strategy and tactics, 14 (Reel 19)
  - Paris consultation, 15 (Reel 19)
  - Parole for Green and Winston, 16 (Reel 19)
  - Pauling petition, 17 (Reel 19)
  - Pauling statement, 18 (Reel 19)
  - Peace Action Center, 19 (Reel 19)
  - Peace News, 20 (Reel 19)
  - Peace Pledge Union, 21 (Reel 19)
  - Peace Research, 22 (Reel 19)
  - Peacemaker, 23 (Reel 19)
  - Pendle Hill (Consultative Peace Council), 24 (Reel 19)
  - Pendle Hill Letter (to President Eisenhower), 25 (Reel 19)
  - Philosophical Library, 26 (Reel 19)
  - Phoenix (yacht), 27 (Reel 19)
  - Pickard, Raleigh (India Letter), 28 (Reel 19)
  - Pioneer Youth of America, 29 (Reel 19)
  - Polaris project, 30 (Reel 19)
  - Political Action for Peace, 31 (Reel 19)
  - Political Action for Peace (MAssachusetts), 32 (Reel 19)
    see Hefner, William
  - Pope, Robert, 33 (Reel 19)
  - Powell House, 34 (Reel 19)
  - Prague meeting, 35 (Reel 19)
  - Prayer House, 1 (Reel 20)
  - Princeton meeting, 2 (Reel 20)
  - The Progressive, 3 (Reel 20)
  - Promoting enduring peace, 4 (Reel 20)
  - Protests against testing, 5 (Reel 20)
  - Provisional Defense Committee (financial), 6 (Reel 20)
  - Provisional study document, 7 (Reel 20)
  - Puerto Rican political prisoners, 8 (Reel 20)
  - Puidoux Conference, III, 1960, Bievres, France, 9 (Reel 20)
  - Quaker conferences in Southern Asia (see Johnson, Russell, in folder J-General), 10 (Reel 20)
  - Quaker Program at the United Nations, 11 (Reel 20)
  - R (General), 12 (Reel 20)
  - Read, Thans, 13 (Reel 20)
  - Reed, Theodore, 14 (Reel 20)
  - Reynolds, Earle, 15 (Reel 20)
  - Reynolds, Ruth, 16 (Reel 20)
  - Rockefeller statement, 17 (Reel 20)
  - Rosenberg case, 18 (Reel 20)